We've only got a week left
until the prelims start.
But nothing we can do right now.
Why don't we just practice
in the hallway again?
We got in trouble for that last time.
They bitched at us for all the
squeaky noise our shoes were making.
Doesn't this school have a
training room or something?
Kuzu High isn't some prestigious school
with fancy shit like that.
We wait until either the volleyball team
finishes using the court.
Or the rain lets up.
What a waste of a precious Saturday.
Okay!
Memorize these!
Uh, let's see, Nanao has a 4.
Yasuhara has an 11, no wait, a 14 I think?
And, uh, Chucky has a...
A woman.
Wow.
How on Earth could you know that
when your back is facing us?!
It's gotta be a trick of
some kind, I just know it!
You always fail 'cuz you try
to memorize them one-by-one.
You'll never be a good point guard
unless you learn to look at the bigger picture.
Just imagine you had to pick
your favorite girl out of 100 of them,
you gotta be able to decide at just a glance
or they won't be impressed.
You don't have to worry about that happening,
because it's a complete fantasy!
Besides, I'm not a horse.
I don't have monocular vision
that lets me see both front and back!
Dude, did you seriously
just compare me to a horse?
Brace yourself for my
patented Rock Chop later!
"Patented"? That's just
a plain old punch, man.
But damn, the rain just won't let up today.
That's fine by me.
We need a break from practice sometimes.
I guess this is the best a
regular high school can offer.
Does this team really stand
any chance... at winning?
Um, hey.
Huh?
We're going to wrap up
our practice for today.
Here are the keys for the gym.
Are you sure? You've only been using it
for about an hour...
The rain ruined everything.
Most of our members didn't even show up.
And we've got midterm
tests next week, anyway.
The badminton team also
started packing up early.
I guess we do get lucky sometimes!
This means we can use the
whole court all we want!
Uh, that's great, but shouldn't some of you
be studying for the upcoming tests, too?
Ain't nothing to worry about!
Oh really? I guess you guys
must be pretty smart, then.
Haha! That's a laugh!
I'm gonna bomb all the tests
just like I always do!
That's not something to be proud of!
It's Shigeyoshi...
Kagami ni senaka mukete ayumu
hodo ni toozakaru yume yo
Massugu kimi to mukiaitai
Dekinai jibun e to "never mind"
Ahiru no Sora
Nagare sagyou de waketeyuku yume
Muki? Fumuki? Iwaba rongai?
Koe mo naku kietetta koe
Tameiki sura denai
Hito no sei ni shitatte owarenai
Me no mae ni kiritatta ima
"Koetai" to kokoro ga sakenderu
Dekinai wake o sagasu nara daredemo dekiru sa
Agaki hashitta sono saki
mada shiranai jibun to deau
Kabe ni kizamikonda rakugaki to "never mind"
Ima asu e to hazume
Light
Nobody was here, so I thought
you canceled practice.
Ah, no.
We take turns using the
gym with the other teams.
Lemme help you out!
Uh, thank you.
We have free reign of the gym for once.
Let's lower the glass boards in the middle.
Sure, we'll rock-paper-scissors
for who does the hard work.
Here we go!
Rock, paper, scissors...!
Shoot!
Please allow me to join the basketball team.
I would like to apologize
for lying to all of you.
Shigeyoshi...
I'm sorry. Please forgive me.
But, the truth is...
...I want to get serious about
playing basketball again.
Please let me join.
Hold up.
We've already seen your true colors.
You can't expect to just
smooth talk your way in now.
Kite.
Despite how our team looks,
we're working really damn hard to reach the top.
Your half-assed passion for the game
is just gonna drag us down.
Go back to playing chemist, fool.
Hey! Be nice, Natsume!
You don't have to act so rude all the-
We're wasting precious time.
Let's get to practicing.
R-right...
The reason I came here...
is because I have true passion for the game.
I'm serious. I want to play basketball.
But what about the chemistry club?
I just finished turning in
my formal resignation to the club advisor.
There's nowhere else for me to go now.
Please allow me to stay with you.
You're not an orphan, jeez.
Since he's this insistent about it,
I don't see any reason to say no.
It's just fine by me, personally.
I don't agree.
Kurumatani...
I can't bring myself to believe him
when he claims to be "serious."
Color me surprised.
Tinytown is totally picking a fight, guys.
Then how can I convince you?
Come out on the court.
Is this for real?
Okay. I get it.
He's fast!
Whoa! A double frappé!
It's a double clutch, dude.
That's one basket for me.
I see... blocks are inevitable for him,
so his playstyle is all
about dealing with them.
This is like watching an adult play a kid.
It doesn't matter how good
Kurumatani is on the court,
he won't be able to stop Shigeyoshi's shots.
There's just too much of a gap in height.
It doesn't matter.
Their skills will be what decide this match.
Whoa, that was a smooth move!
And now, we're even.
Is it just me, or is Kurumatani acting
a little strange today?
He was the one most excited about the idea
of Shigeyoshi joining us.
Did he just get really upset
at being lied to, or what?
You should be... guarding me more closely.
Huh?
I'm not missing a single shot today.
He scored from long-range
on me in a one-on-one...
Dammit!
There it is!
What's the matter?
We've barely been at it for 10 minutes.
Is this really how you play
when you're "serious"?
A'ight! That's enough!
We can't waste any more time.
Get ready to start practice!
Hey! I think this guy
is at his limit already.
What? No...
Hit the bench and rest up.
But I...
You're in the way!
Sekiya! Sub out with him!
Hold it right there!
Ow!
Whoa! The girls are invading our turf!
Why are you guys bullying
the new guy like that?
Don't the freshman have
their own training schedule to follow?
Jerks.
Yeah, well, this guy doesn't
even look like a freshman.
Speak up for yourself when you need a break.
Don't let anybody else determine
what your limits are.
Senpai...
I'm not done yet.
I can still keep playing.
Oh my gosh... that was
high enough to be a dunk!
And now, we're even once again.
That was definitely a foul. Just now.
No way, that's typical contact
for under the basket.
They've been at it for 30 minutes already.
That Mokichi guy is pretty
decent for hanging on so long.
Yeah.
He's just trying to skip
out on actual practice.
I knew a guy like that back in middle school.
It definitely doesn't seem
that way to me, though.
Huh?
That guy has gone... well beyond his limit.
A crossover!
Not yet. Let's keep going.
I'm sick and tired... of shouldering
people's expectations.
And I'm already used...
to people being disappointed in me.
But... the truth is...
none of that ever really
mattered to me at all.
All of the seniors... on the day
of our very last tournament together...
I've gotta block!
Saijo
Kozu
Tsukishima...
What I feared more than anything...
was losing the light you brought.
Holy shit, check that dunk! Badass!
He plays pretty rough
despite looking so timid.
He's showing off too damn much.
Looks like... I win.
He just smiled!
I didn't think that was possible for him!
What the hell gave you that impression?
Shigeyoshi...
Smug jerk...
I looked up the word "regret"...
...in the dictionary.
I realized... I was an idiot.
See ya.
Bye.
Wait, isn't this your friend, Kyoko?
How terrible, don't you have an umbrella?
I forgot mine... back at school.
Even though it's raining so hard?
Quick, find a towel!
The truth is... that I did like
you back then, Tsukishima.
Yeah. I know.
And... I still do now.
I know that, too.
Goodbye.
Wait, Kyoko!
What's with you?
I don't know what's going on,
but you're being way too hard on him.
You should at least listen
to what he has to say.
Senpai... I've decided
to start playing basketball once again.
If things go well,
my team will go up against
the one from your school in the second round.
A huge mistake... that I'll
never be able to undo.
That is the burden... with
which I must live with.
That was so mean of you, Kurumatani.
Shigeyoshi actually came to us
without needing any convincing.
Don't you want to play on
the same team with him?
I think... there really are
people in the world too sick
to play basketball even though they want to.
That's why... it was impossible for me
to just forgive Mokichi for lying about that.
Kurumatani...
But...
...I'm glad it wasn't true.
In the end, I still really do want to play basketball...
together with Mokichi.
We have a new member I
need to introduce to you.
Or at least, I wanted to, but...
...he's apparently out
sick with a cold today.
You gotta be kidding!
So now, I'll just skip
to today's announcements.
As you all know, the midterm
tests will begin tomorrow.
Generally speaking, all teams are on break
during the testing period...
What?!
Wha-?! Hold on a damn second!
We only have 6 days left
until the prelims start!
And I still haven't been able
to get my shots to go in!
If we stop practicing this
week then we're doomed!
Ban the tests instead!
I'm fully aware. Relax,
I'm not a complete tyrant.
For the following four days that
the tests are being held...
...you boys are free to make use
of the empty gym in whatever way you see fit.
Oh sweet, that's an awesome deal.
This is perfect.
Especially since school gets out at noon
during test week!
It'll be like a mini training camp!
That means we'll be able to
pack our schedule totally full.
For sure!
Midterms! For the win! Yes!
Uh, just one more thing.
If any of you end up with a failing grade
on the midterm tests,
I'll pull you from the prelims.
Seriously...?
Dead serious.
WHAAAAT?!
Okay, that's a big problem.
For now, just raise your hand
if you expect to fail a test.
Okay!
That's basically the entire team!
What about that Mokichi guy who just joined?
Maybe we can drop him
before he ruins it for us.
Worry about yourselves first!
Shigeyoshi went to THE Saijo Middle School,
so he must be plenty smart and talented!
For real?!
Jeez, what a damn glory hound!
Anyways, I think our best
bet is to focus on just
the key subjects and study
in groups split by grade.
What tests are tomorrow?
Do you all know what to expect?
Have you been taking notes in class?
Nope.
Beats me.
Who uses notebooks?
You can memorize info by
eating textbooks, you know.
P-please give me a few pages!
I'll top them with some mayo!
So hey, "Kings of the Animal Jungle" is on tonight.
Can I go home early?
Okay, I've had it up to HERE with you guys!
Starting right now, NOBODY can leave the gym
without my express permission!
HUH?!
First Semester Midterm Schedule
Day 4
Day 3
Day 2
Day 1
Freshmen
Sophomores
Seniors
English
Modern Lit.
History
Math
Physics
Classic Lit.
Science
World
History
Reading
Social
Studies
Classic Lit.
Modern Lit.
Geography
Math
Chemistry
Japanese
English
Economics
Reading
Midterm Tests
Modern Lit.
Physics
Days left until tourney prelims: 4
Screen Practice Formation Practice
Kanagawa School of Medical Science
Secondary Hospital
Excuse me.
Is Nurse Yabuuchi from
the Internal Medicine department available?
I'm her younger sister.
Uh, let's see. Does anyone know
where Ms. Yabuuchi is right now?
In room 305, doing her check
up on Mrs. Kurumatani.
Oh, then I'll just head directly over
to that room, if that's okay.
These flowers I brought are
actually for that patient.
Oh, how nice.
Yuka Kurumatani
Good afternoon.
Oh my.
Madoka?!
Um, I'm... s-s-sorry....!
You should at least knock
before you come in, jeez!
It's all right, I don't mind.
I'm so sorry.
I've still got some nice curves on me, huh?
Mrs. Kurumatani!
Prairie gentian flowers, right?
Such a wonderful aroma.
Thank you.
Oh, it's nothing.
So why aren't you at school right now?
Don't tell me you're skipping class again!
We're out early because it's test week!
Oh wow, and you came all the
way out here to visit me?
You should have come after
test week was over, then!
Don't make Mrs. Kurumatani feel bad
for interrupting your study time!
Please, it's okay.
I had to... come and return this.
Hold on, isn't that the
bracelet she asked you to...?
You didn't go through with it, then?
I'm sorry.
I'm so relieved!
Huh?
That boy is bright enough
to recognize who made it.
I think he would have
figured it out right away.
So I regretted asking you to give it to him.
Mrs. Kurumatani...
I'm so glad he didn't end up getting it!
Thank you so much, Madoka.
Don't mention it.
So, would you mind staying
to chat with me for a little while?
You came right when I
was feeling a bit bored.
Oh, sure! My pleasure.
Recommended Sunset
Tourist Spots
Wow! That was so much fun!
She even gave me this tasty-looking apple.
Mrs. Yuka really is so charming.
Oh please, have a little more respect.
She was so considerate after
you barged in like that.
You should have followed through and come up
with some way to give
Sora that bracelet, jeez.
What a nice aroma...
Hey, Sis?
Hm?
Did Mrs. Yuka... undergo surgery?
What?
I noticed earlier... that
she had a scar on her chest.
Oh, that's from not too long ago.
You have some sharp eyes, Madoka.
Is she all right now?
Well, it certainly wasn't
a very difficult surgery.
They just cut her open and
then sewed her back up.
What does that mean?
I've never heard of a
surgery like that before.
It's true.
They went in and then stopped.
Do you... understand what that means?
Whoa, another one?!
You're on fire, Tinytown!
You haven't missed a single shot all day!
I haven't even had a chance
to touch the ball, dammit!
Well, get used to it!
This shrimp is truly something else.
I'm more impressed by how
he gets open to shoot,
rather than his accuracy rate.
I can only imagine
One more time!
how many difficult trials he's overcome
with that small frame of his...
My excitement is growing
with every day that we get closer to our first game.
We've assembled... some serious firepower!
Hitori ja umaku ikanaku temo
Kikkake nante tanjun sa
Mienai deguchi ni hikaru ga sashite
Asu wa soko ni arunda
Hitori nanka ja nakatta
Kono me ni utsuru keshiki no naka ni
Kimi ga ireba doko made datte ikeru sa
Kitto genkai nante nainda
Kimi to ireba tsuyoku narunda
Nando demo tachiagatte susunde ikou
Oh oh oh, oh oh oh, oh oh oh,
Saigo no ichibyou made
Akiramenaide busukatte
Kono michi no saki wa
kanarazu kagayaiteru kara
I went and bruised it... right
after she gave it to me.
I need to focus. I have tests tomorrow.
I feel sick...
Ahiru no Sora
Next Time: Undiscovered Talent
Next time: "Undiscovered Talent."